<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SecondHandSmartGuy Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SecondHandSmartGuy Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 19:50:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Wanna Be a Monster</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/i-wanna-be-a-monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 19:50:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/i-wanna-be-a-monster/</guid>
      <description>This is something that I have been thinking a lot lately.
How does history remember us?
Every generation has these huge events that they&amp;rsquo;re remembered for and because of the simplifications that are common for a human mind, often we separate the participants of those events into &amp;ldquo;good guys&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;bad guys&amp;rdquo;. As history goes on, we seem to put more and more people into the &amp;ldquo;bad guys&amp;rdquo; category. A very small number of people have been remembered as universally good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why So Scared?</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/why-so-scared/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 09:38:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/why-so-scared/</guid>
      <description>I can already see that this post is going to be very long since I don&amp;rsquo;t really have it compiled in my head completely, but I want to talk about what follows, so thank you for choosing to fly Damad Bullshit Airlines, strap in, there&amp;rsquo;s going to be some turbulence.
I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about science a lot lately. What I&amp;rsquo;m about to do in this post has no science behind it, at least not that I know of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Look Up?</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/should-you-look-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:45:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/should-you-look-up/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a little late to the party, but yesterday I finally saw &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t look up&amp;rdquo;. Since I&amp;rsquo;m not a movie critic, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about movies, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into that. However, this movie did make me ask myself one question. Before I ask it, I first need to tell you a story.
One of my closest friends, for a decade now, is also one of the smartest people I know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you want to be a scientist?</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/to-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 14:44:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/to-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, future scientist.
So you want to be a scientist? Help the World. Improve our understanding of the universe, improve the way we live our lives, improve the quality of life, our health? Good luck! I hope you do. I was never brave enough for that. Because I was never brave enough for that, I became an engineer. A lower class. Engineering is a wonderful thing, but we are just fixing things with tools you, scientists, provide us with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Is Going Exactly Where It&#39;s Supposed To Go!</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/annual-letter-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 01:47:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/annual-letter-2021/</guid>
      <description>It was the summer of 2008 when I saw a movie that would change the trajectory of my life to the path it took to bring me to who I am today. I was completely unaware of the problematic life of the main actor, obviously unaware and unprepared for the next decade or so of the movie universe that that movie will start. I mean, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even 11 yet, how could I be?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
