<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SecondHandSmartGuy Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SecondHandSmartGuy Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 23:42:07 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Not a Hobby</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/its-not-a-hobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 23:42:07 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/its-not-a-hobby/</guid>
      <description>Past couple of days I’ve been listening to In Rainbows by Radiohead over and over again. Put aside my sick love for Radiohead, listening to this made me think about some things. Let’s break them down.
This is for everyone that likes to claim they’re educated, well put together, progressive, intelligent, “better than everyone else.” For you, “renaissance” people who think they’ve left behind ordinary people:
You’re boring.
You’re as boring as a bowl of plain oatmeal, except you don’t even help control cholesterol, and you’re not rich in fiber.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Letter 2023</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/annual-letter-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 15:31:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/annual-letter-2023/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone! How are you? I hope you’re doing well. This is like a fourth version of this letter and I have no clue what to write. I haven’t been writing this year, because honestly, I didn’t know what to write, I didn’t want to force it and I deep fried all of that in laziness. Also, I have no clue what this letter will turn out to be. The first time I wrote one of these, I was thinking about the future, technology, science, and progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Happy - Annual Letter 2022</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/be-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 15:00:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/be-happy/</guid>
      <description>Hi. What’s up? How’s it going? Are you happy? What a year… huh? Honestly, through ups and downs, for me it was a banger. A lot of soul searching. I found out things about myself I didn’t know. Some of them I liked and some I didn’t. I’m trying to change. I admitted it, I’m not a very easy person to be around. I’m working on it. Cut me some slack (Don’t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Did Dreams Die?</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/when-did-dreams-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 18:23:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/when-did-dreams-die/</guid>
      <description>I had some weird realizations lately. I decided to relax. Just be normal. Go out with friends, go on field trips, you know, “enjoy” life. And… it REALLY didn’t work. I was never more stressed in my life. I felt miserable. This is what the days would look like in the past summer. I’d finish work, and phone home that I won’t be eating lunch at home. I’d go out with people and not like a crazy amount of people, just my regular group of people that I’d go out with even outside this “experiment”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Am Difficult</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/i-am-difficult/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 23:35:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/i-am-difficult/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a very difficult person to be around. Phew. That kinda felt good to admit. No one wants that. Everybody wants to be that easy going, approachable type. Well&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not.
I lose interest in conversations extremely fast. I hate small talk. I know everyone says that, but through my &amp;ldquo;research&amp;rdquo;, I call bullshit. People don&amp;rsquo;t want to talk about anything deeper than what makes them feel superior. I challenge you, just for yourself, stand in front of a mirror, and call out your insecurities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Am Ready</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/i-am-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:30:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/i-am-ready/</guid>
      <description>Usually I have at least a title. Now I don&amp;rsquo;t. I know vaguely what I want to say, but that&amp;rsquo;s about it. And I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll make a big intro to this. I&amp;rsquo;ll just say this.
I want to feel sad. I want to cry. I fooled myself into thinking that being happy is the final goal. FUCK. THAT. I want to feel it all. I want the experience of failure to bring me every emotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Only Thing You Can Do Is Hope</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/the-only-thing-you-can-do-is-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 13:25:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/the-only-thing-you-can-do-is-hope/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days back, my friend and colleague sent me an interesting text. She was out on a company organized dinner for women in our company. She made a, kinda sarcastic remark that went something like this:
After this I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether to feel lonely or to give birth to a child.
This kickstarted a circle of thoughts in my mind about loneliness. I&amp;rsquo;ve written about relationships before, and just like then, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure this will make sense completely, because some of the things are just me thinking as I go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Am Not Happy</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/i-am-not-happy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 23:46:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/i-am-not-happy/</guid>
      <description>Throughout my life I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my views on things many times. It usually happens when I figure out that I&amp;rsquo;m wrong about something. It can go back and forth, it&amp;rsquo;s exhausting. I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend thinking as an activity, it can get very boring. This time, I would like to tell a story of how, after many years of thinking, I may have unlocked the best place for a good state of my mind so far and I currently see no other way to improve it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is why I don&#39;t care anymore</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/why-i-do-not-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 21:31:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/why-i-do-not-care/</guid>
      <description>Less than a year ago, I was a militant pro vaxxer. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even fathom the idea that someone doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to get vaccinated and I had absolutely no sympathy for people that caught COVID and weren&amp;rsquo;t vaccinated.
Do I still think we should get vaccinated? Yes, absolutely. There&amp;rsquo;s more than solid evidence that it works and it&amp;rsquo;s saving lives.
Where I differ from my past self is that I don&amp;rsquo;t think mandates are a good idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Wanna Be a Monster</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/i-wanna-be-a-monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 19:50:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/i-wanna-be-a-monster/</guid>
      <description>This is something that I have been thinking a lot lately.
How does history remember us?
Every generation has these huge events that they&amp;rsquo;re remembered for and because of the simplifications that are common for a human mind, often we separate the participants of those events into &amp;ldquo;good guys&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;bad guys&amp;rdquo;. As history goes on, we seem to put more and more people into the &amp;ldquo;bad guys&amp;rdquo; category. A very small number of people have been remembered as universally good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why So Scared?</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/why-so-scared/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 09:38:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/why-so-scared/</guid>
      <description>I can already see that this post is going to be very long since I don&amp;rsquo;t really have it compiled in my head completely, but I want to talk about what follows, so thank you for choosing to fly Damad Bullshit Airlines, strap in, there&amp;rsquo;s going to be some turbulence.
I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about science a lot lately. What I&amp;rsquo;m about to do in this post has no science behind it, at least not that I know of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Look Up?</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/should-you-look-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:45:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/should-you-look-up/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a little late to the party, but yesterday I finally saw &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t look up&amp;rdquo;. Since I&amp;rsquo;m not a movie critic, and I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about movies, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into that. However, this movie did make me ask myself one question. Before I ask it, I first need to tell you a story.
One of my closest friends, for a decade now, is also one of the smartest people I know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you want to be a scientist?</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/to-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 14:44:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/to-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, future scientist.
So you want to be a scientist? Help the World. Improve our understanding of the universe, improve the way we live our lives, improve the quality of life, our health? Good luck! I hope you do. I was never brave enough for that. Because I was never brave enough for that, I became an engineer. A lower class. Engineering is a wonderful thing, but we are just fixing things with tools you, scientists, provide us with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Is Going Exactly Where It&#39;s Supposed To Go!</title>
      <link>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/annual-letter-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 01:47:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://secondhandsmartguy.github.io/posts/annual-letter-2021/</guid>
      <description>It was the summer of 2008 when I saw a movie that would change the trajectory of my life to the path it took to bring me to who I am today. I was completely unaware of the problematic life of the main actor, obviously unaware and unprepared for the next decade or so of the movie universe that that movie will start. I mean, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even 11 yet, how could I be?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
